Guide to the Denise Levertov Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 6. Printed Materials
  - b. Chapbooks
    - Wakoski, Diane. The last poem /, by Diane Wakoski & Tough company / by Charles Bukowski. [A New Year's Greeting from the Black Sparrow Press, 1976]. Santa Barbara, [Calif.]: Black Sparrow Press, 1976. [11] p.; 21 cm., 1976 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Waldron, Hermine. Granite blossoms / Hermine Waldron. Portsmouth, N.H.: Waldron, c1983 (South Berwick, Me.: Chronicle Print Shop) 61 p.; 23 cm., 1983 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Warren, Eugene. Rumors of Light / Eugene Warren. St. Louis: Grafiktrakts, 1974., 1974 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Weaver, Mary Jo. What's wrong with being right?: The Santa Clara Lectures, Vol. 2, no. 3/, Mary Jo Weaver. Santa Clara, CA (Department of Religious Studies, Santa Clara, CA 95053): Santa Clara University, [1996 Apr. 15]. 17 pp., 1996 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Weiss, Sigmund. Poems written during my irresponsible youth plus ... / by Sigmund Weiss. Stony Brook, N.Y.: Weiss, c1976. 16 p.; 22 cm., 1976 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - West, Austin, 1913-. I am the sea and 61 other poems / by Austin West. South Portland, Maine: n.p., [1964]. [40] p.: ill.; 19 cm., 1964 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Wilson, Robert Alfred Jump, 1922-. Faulkner on Fire Island /, by Robert A. Wilson. New York: Phoenix Bookshop, 1979. [4], 7, [1] p.: 1 facsim.; 18 cm., 1979 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Wilson, Robert Alfred Jump, 1922-. In the city of Aldus /, by Robert A. Wilson. New York: R. Wilson: Phoenix Bookshop, c1985. 18 p.: facsims.; 18 cm., 1985 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Winchester Cathedral. Winchester Cathedral; a short history for visitors. Winchester, Printed for the Dean and Chapter by Warren & Son, Limited [1925?] 16 p. 19 cm., 1925 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Window. Allentown, [Pa.]: Muhlenberg Poetry Workshop, 1962. [33]p. illus., 22 cm., 1962 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Yud Teth Kislev: the story of the universally famous chasidic festival of the 19th day of Kislev, commemorating the liberation of Rabbi Schneur Zalman of Liady (author of the Shulchan Aruch and Tanya)--the "Old Rabbi" of Chabad chasidism. Second Edition. Brooklyn: Ozar Hachasidim, c1957. 15 p. 16 cm., 1957 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Zhivkov, Todor. By and for the people: building an advanced Socialist society in Bulgaria /, edited by Marilyn Bechtel. New York: NWR Publications, 1977. 143 p.; 18 cm., 1977 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - c. Articles
    - "Agreeing to Grow", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Albach, Carl L. "Miracle or a wonder of construction?" Consulting Engineer, 1965 Dec. (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Aleshire, Joan. "Some notes on translation: imperatives, sacrifices, rewards" A View From the Loft, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Alexander, Paul. "Holy secrets." [psychiatric records of deceased poets Sylvia Plath and Anne Sexton]. Nation.--vol. 254, no. 11 (March 23, 1992): 385 (3 pages)., 1992 Mar. 23 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Alvarez, A. "The playful pianist: Alfred Brendel, widely considered to be the world's greatest classical player, is not at all what you might expect." New Yorker.--vol. 72, no. 6 (April 1, 1996): 49 (7 pages)., 1996 Apr. 1 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - "An interview with Michael Harrington" Harmony Magazine, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - [Hiss, Tony ]. "Annals of Transportation: Light rail." New Yorker.--vol. 65, no. 3 (March 6, 1989): 70 (12 pages)., 1989 Mar. 6 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - "Art Works" [On Nikolai Goodman] West Seattle Herald / White Center News., 1994 Aug. 10 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Atwood, Margaret. "Poem homelanding" Radcliffe Quarterly, 1986 Dec. (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - "A Vanished Present: The Memoirs of Alexander Pasternak" Chapter 22, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Baer, Richard A. "Quaker Silence, Catholic Liturgy and Pentecostal Glossolalia--Some functional similarities," from Perspectives on the New Pentecostalism, Russell P. Spittler, ed. Grand Rapids: Baker Book House Co., 1976, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Baker, Nicholson. "The author vs. the library" [San Francisco, California, Public Library]. New Yorker.--vol. 72, no. 31 (Oct 14, 1996): 50 (11 pages)., 1996 Oct. 14 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Baker, Nicholson. "Discards" [replacement of card catalogs with on-line public access catalogs]. New Yorker.--vol. 70, no. 7 (April 4, 1994): 64 (21 pages)., 1994 Apr. 4 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Balaban, John. "Doing Good," The Hudson Review.--Vol. 30, no. 4, 1977 Winter, offprint (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Balaban, John. "Viewing the New World Order" Witness.--Vol. 6, no. 1, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Barnes, Julian. "Letter from London: The Maggie years" [British ex-prime minister Margaret Thatcher writes memoirs]. New Yorker .--vol. 69, no. 38 (Nov 15, 1993): 82 (8 pages)., 1993 Nov. 15 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Berg, Stephen. "Habakkuk" from Congregation: Contemporary Writers read the Jewish Bible /, edited by David Rosenberg. San Diego: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, c1987., 1993 Nov. 15 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Berger, John. "Keeping a rendezvous :the revolution of '89." Nation.--vol. 250, no. 18 (May 7, 1990): 625 (4 pages)., 1990 May 7 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Berger, Peter L. "The Problem of multiples realities: Alfred Schutz and Robert Musil", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Bernstein, Theodore. 1 facsim. with holographic notes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Berry, Wendell. "Two Economies", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Birkerts, Sven. "Hamann's Bone: a note on the language of poetry", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Bissell, Trim. "Going to extremes: my 17 years as a fugitive from the FBI" Pacific Northwest, 1987 June (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Blaydes, Sophie. "Metaphors of life and death in the poetry of Denise Levertov and Sylvia Plath", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Blum, David. "Going to the core" [Richard Goode]. New Yorker.--vol. 68, no. 19 (June 29, 1992): 39 (19 pages)., 1992 June 29 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Blumenthal, Michael. "The writer's relationship to justice" Poets & Writers Magazine., 1991 Jan. - Feb. (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - Bocock, Maclin. "The Baxter's Daughter or a tale of Holy Russia," The Southern Review, 1988 Summer (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Bocock, Maclin. "Play me 'Stormy Weather,' Please" Southern Review, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - Boeing Headquarters to Duwamish River: "Biblical Journey to Liberation, Passover--Good Friday", 1990 Apr. 13 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Bogen, Dan. "The Fundamental Skeptic" The Nation, 1986 Jan. 18 (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - Boruch, Marianne. "The Sound of It" The Southern Review.--vol. 30, no. 2 (Spring, 1994):334 (16 pages)., 1994 Spring (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Bosnak, Robert. "The Dirty Needle: images of the inferior analyst" Spring, 1984, offprint (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Boston, Anne. "Women Poets: The Quiet Revolutionaries" Good Housekeeping, 1986 Nov. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Bowen, Kevin. "Some other poets of the war" Poet Love, 1994 Spring (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Brown, Norman O. "Apocalypse: the Place of Mystery in the life of the mind", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Brown, Norman O. "The Prophetic Tradition", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Burford, William. "Invoking the Muse: Review of Cesare Pavese's Hard Labor: Poems" Lone Star Book Review, 1980 Mar. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Burton-Christie, Douglas. "The Literature of Nature and the quest for the sacred." The Way Supplement.--No. 81, 1994 Autumn (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Burton-Christie, Douglas. "Mapping the Sacred Landscape," Horizons.--Vol. 21, no. 1, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Burton-Christie, Douglas. "We already have all that we seek," Weavings.--Vol. 10, no. 3, 1993 May - June (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Canetti, Elias; Hargraves, John. "Notes from Hampstead: The Writer's Notes: 1954-1971." [excerpt]. American Poetry Review.--vol. 26, no. 6 (Nov-Dec, 1997): 23S (3 pages)., 1997 Nov. - Dec. (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Carlisle, Susan G. "French Homes and French Character" (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Carroll, James. "Why we disagree with the Pope... yet stay in the church" Church Watch, 1995 June (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Cheever, Benjamin. "The new deaf" [books on tape]. New Yorker .--vol. 71, no. 8 (April 17, 1995): 116 (1 page)., 1995 Apr. 17 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Chisholm, Patricia. "An extraordinary capacity to forgive," Maclean's, 1997 Feb. 10 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - "Christian conscience and modern warfare," from La Civilita Cattolica, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Clark, Howard. "Western pacifists and wars of liberation" The Nonviolent Activist, 1986 July - Aug. (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Close, Henry T. "On Parenting", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Cohen, Derek. "The question of Shylock," Brick, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Collecott, Diana. "Remembering oneself: the reputation and later poetry of H.D.," Critical Quarterly.--Vol. 27, no. 1, n.d., offprint + ALS (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Cooke, Bernard. "God-with-us calls for new type of papacy," National Catholic Reporter, 1995 Mar. 10 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Cooke, Bernard. "Renewal of papacy will transform church," National Catholic Reporter, 1995 Feb. 24 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Cronon, William. "The trouble with wilderness" The New York Times Magazine., 1995 Aug. 13 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - "The Cult of Saints in the Middle Ages and Renaissance" J. Paul Getty Museum, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Danto, Arthur C. "A Guide to Horrors: the 1985 Biennial Exhibition" The Nation, 1985 Apr. 27 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Danto, Arthur C. "Art: John Singer Sargeant" The Nation, 1986 Dec. 13 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Danto, Arthur C. "Art: Paul Klee" The Nation, 1987 Apr. 4 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Danto, Arthur C. Review of George Innes's "The New Path," The Nation, 1985 June 8 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Davis, Felton. "The Arc bends towards God's Justice", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - "Death as a friend: Joseph Cardinal Bernadin," New York Times Magazine, 1996 Dec. 1 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Denby, David. "Buried alive" [pop culture's affect on children] New Yorker.--vol. 72, no. 19 (July 15, 1996): 48 (10 pages)., 1996 July 15 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Denby, David. "Does Homer have legs?" [curriculum of literature courses and political correctness]. New Yorker.--vol. 69, no. 28 (Sept. 6, 1993): 52 (16 pages)., 1993 Sept. 6 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - De Vinck, Catherine. "Blessed are the peacemakers" Pax Christi USA, 1988 Spring (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Dictionary of Literary Biography: proof fragment, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Dooling, Richard. "Bush pigs" [short story]. New Yorker.--vol. 70, no. 32 (Oct 10, 1994): 82 (7 pages)., 1994 Oct. 10 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Douglas, Deborah Smith. "Of woodstoves, burnout, and the living flame of love," Spiritual Life, 1994 Fall (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Doyle, Brian. "Joey's Doll's other arm.." Orion, 1997 Summer (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Drinan, Robert F., OSJ. "Should Robert McNamara go to prison?" National Catholic Reporter, 1995 Apr. 21 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Dubus, Andre. "Witness" [highway accident victim's encounter with a witness to his accident]. New Yorker.--vol. 73, no. 20 (July 21, 1997): 33 (4 pages)., 1997 July 21 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Dunn, Stephen. "The good, the not so good," AWP Newsletter, 1986 Nov. - Dec. (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Egan, Eileen. "War: reversing the works of mercy", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - "Eternal rest, Henri Nouwen," The Catholic Reporter, 1996 Dec. (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Falk, Donald A. "Endangered Forest Resources in the U.S.: Integrated Strategies for Conservation...", n.d., 1 TMs (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Fallaci, Orianna. "Interview with Lech Walesa", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Felstiner, John. "The Biography of a poem," The New Republic, 1984 Apr. 2 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Felstiner, John. "Kafka and the Golem--translating Paul Celan" Prooftexts, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - Felstiner, John. "Mother tongue, Holy tongue: on translating and not translating Paul Celan," Comparative Literature.--Vol. 38, no. 2, 1986 Spring (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - Felstiner, John. "Mother tongue, Holy tongue: on translating and not translating Paul Celan," Comparative Literature.--Vol. 38, no. 2, 1986 Spring (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - Felstiner, John. "Paul Celan: The Strain of Jewishness," Commentary, 1985 Apr. (Box 24, Folder 49)
    - Felstiner, John. "Reconsiderations: Paul Celan--the biography of a poem", 1984 Apr. 2 (Box 24, Folder 50)
    - Felstiner, John. "Translating Celan" ACTS.--vol. 8-9, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - Felstiner, John. "'Ziv, that light': translation and tradition in Paul Celan," New Literary History.--Vol. 18, 1986 - 1987 (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - Field, Ross. "The fate of doing nothing right", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - Fields, Kenneth. "Communities of writers" Notes in the margins, 1992 Fall (Box 24, Folder 54)
    - Fink, Ida. "Two Stories" ["An afternoon on the grass" and A second scrap of time". New Yorker.--vol. 73, no. 5 (March 24, 1997): 72 (4 pages)., 1997 Mar. 24 (Box 24, Folder 55)
    - Fry, Stephen. "Playing Oscar: Oscar Wilde had always been a strange presence in the author's life, but never more so than when he played him in a new movie" ['Wilde']. New Yorker.--vol. 73, no. 16 (June 16, 1997): 82 (7 pages)., 1997 June 16 (Box 24, Folder 56)
    - Gates, Henry Louis, Jr. "The Weaning of America: Culture of Complaint" New Yorker.--vol. 69, no. 9 (April 19, 1993): 113 (5 pages)., 1993 Apr. 19 (Box 24, Folder 57)
    - Geller, Laura. "Encountering the Divine Presence", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 58)
    - Gelpi, Albert. "The map for the periplum," American Poetry.--Vol. 1, no. 2, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Gianvito, John. "The language of film", 1987 Oct. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Gibney, Arthur. "The manure spreader", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Gilbert, Alan. "Exquisite balances," from Denver Quarterly", 1992 Autumn (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Gilbert, Sandra. On Denise Levertov, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Gitlin, Todd. "Poetry goes public--to unlock the manacles of the mind," Alternative Features Service., n.d. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Goslow, Brian. "Levertov views world candidly," The Student Voice., 1987 Nov. 12 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Griffiths, Paul. "Schnittke: Seventh Symphony" [Avery Fisher Hall, New York, New York]. New Yorker.--vol. 70, no. 3 (March 7, 1994): 91 (3 pages)., 1994 Mar. 7 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Grobel, Lawrence. "Interview with Andrew Greeley," Modern Maturity, 1996 May - June (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Gross, Harvey. "Compound ghost, triple devil: on critique and the demonic in Mann and Eliot", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Gross, Netty C. "Baptism by force," Jerusalem Post International Edition., 1994 Jan. 29 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Haines, John. "On a certain attention to the world", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Haines, John. review of Schullery's Mark of the Bear, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Hamill, Sam. "Salt and Honey: Denise Levertov revisited." American Poetry Review.--vol. 20, no. 6 (Nov-Dec, 1991):39 (4 pages)., 1991 Nov. - Dec. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Hamill, Sam. "Shadow Work" American Poetry Review., 1986 Nov. - Dec. (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Hampl, Patricia. "Reflections on a golden city: Prague" The Sophisticated Traveler (New York Times Magazine), 1995 Sept. 12 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Hardwick, Elizabeth. "The life and death of Caryl Chessman", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Hardy, Barbara. review of Adcock, ed. The Faber Book of 20th century Women's Poetry., n.d. (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Hatlen, Burton. "'Feminine technologies': George Oppen talks at Denise Levertov." American Poetry Review.--vol. 22, no. 3 (May-June, 1993): 9 (6 pages)., 1994 May - June (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Hatlen, Burton. "'Feminine technologies': George Oppen talks at Denise Levertov." American Poetry Review.--vol. 22, no. 3 (May-June, 1993): 9 (6 pages)., 1994 May - June (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Hauerwas, Stanley. "The significance of vision: toward an aesthetic ethic" from Vision and Virtue, 1994 May - June (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - [Robbins, Anthony]. "Hayden Carruth: an interview by Anthony Robbins." American Poetry Review.--Vol. 22, no. 5 (Sept-Oct, 1993): 47 (9 pages)., 1993 Sept. - Oct. (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Head of a young girl, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Helms, Alan. "Intricate song's last measure," Sewanee Review.--Vol. 87, no. 2, 1979 Spring (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Hemp, Christine. "The reek of writing success" Santa Fe Reporter, 1994 Mar. 2 - 8 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Heyen, William. "An open letter to the Brockport College community." American Poetry Review.--vol. 18, no. 3 (May-June, 1989): 7 (1 page)., 1989 May - June (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Hiestand, Emily. "South of Ultima Thule", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Hines, Sandra. "The misbehavin' tourist", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Hoffer, William. "A magic ratio recurs throughout art and nature", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Holub, Miroslav. "The Dimension of the Present Moment", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Holub, Miroslav. "Interferon" or "On Theatre", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Howard, Richard. "The Ghettoization of Poetry" PEN Literary Awards Keynote Address, 1996 May 20 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Hrotsvitha. "Dulcitas", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Hrotsvitha. "Paphnutius", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Humphrey, William. "The Mountain of Miracles" The New Yorker, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - [Author unknown] "In Praise of Creative Misinterpretation" Arts Magazine, 1978 Mar (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Isaacson, Judith Magyar. "Seed of Sarah: A Memoir" The Yale Review [signed offprint], 1984 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Islas, Arturo. "The Blind" ZYZZYVA Vol.2, no. 1, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Jones, Mary Paumier. "The Storytelling Animal" The Georgia Review, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Kemper, Vicki. "A Prophet's Vision and Grace" Sojourners, 1987 Dec 12 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Kennelly, Brendon. "Six Poems from Cromwell", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Kenner, Hugh. On George Oppen's Collected Poems. New York Times Book Review, 1975 Oct 19 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Killick, John. Please give me back my personality!: Writing and Dementia, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Klein, Joe. "In God they trust; Washington faces a new challenge: should it let the churches take over the inner cities?". New Yorker.--vol. 73, no. 16 (June 16, 1997): 40 (9 pages)., 1997 June 16 (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Kohl, Herbert. "Space Lessons" The Nation, 1986 Feb 15 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Konrad, George. "The high priest of frivolity" [short story]. New Yorker.--vol. 68, no. 3 (March 9, 1992): 31 (9 pages)., 1992 Mar. 9 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Kownacki, Mary Lou. "One Day At a Time" Pax Christi USA, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 47)
    - Kramer, Jane. "Letter from Europe: Monthelie, December 19". New Yorker.--vol. 65, no. 46 (Jan. 1, 1990): 46 (17 pages)., 1990 Jan 1 (Box 25, Folder 48)
    - Lacey, Margaret. "The Haunted Bicycle" (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - Lacey, Paul A. "All Things Sweet and Useful" Earlhamite, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Lacey, Paul A. "Teaching as a Double Dialogue" New Directions for Teaching and Learning no. 4, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 51)
    - Lacey, Paul A. "Views of a Luddite" College and Research Libraries, 1982 Mar (Box 25, Folder 52)
    - Lacey, Paul A. Your Young Shall See Visions, Your Old Shall Dream Dreams (Box 25, Folder 53)
    - Lambert, Craig. "Cantos and the Stem Christie: on James Laughlin" Harvard Magazine, 1995 Jan-Feb (Box 25, Folder 54)
    - Lane, Anthony. "Scripture Rescripted: The New Testament and Psalms: An Inclusive Version." New Yorker.--vol. 71, no. 30 (Oct 2, 1995): 98 (3 pages)., 1995 Oct 2 (Box 25, Folder 55)
    - Lane, Anthony. "Scripture Rescripted: The New Testament and Psalms: An Inclusive Version." New Yorker.--vol. 71, no. 30 (Oct 2, 1995): 98 (3 pages)., 1995 Oct 2 (Box 25, Folder 56)
    - Lask, Thomas. Old New Directions [Chronicle of Higher Education], n.d. (Box 25, Folder 57)
    - Laughlin, James -- interview with Robert Dana. Against the Grain., 1987 (Box 25, Folder 58)
    - Lee, Brian. Review of Vendler et al. The Harper American Literature, Vols. 1-2. TLS, 1987 May 22 (Box 25, Folder 59)
    - Le Mieux, Dotty. "At the Railway Station", 1976 Jul 23 (Box 25, Folder 60)
    - Levertov, Denise. "The Draft in 1979" Follies, 1979 Nov (Box 25, Folder 61)
    - Levertov, Denise. "Each in Her Own Voice" New York Times Book Review, 1963 Nov 3 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Levertov, Denise. "The 'Great Mother' Celebrates Humanity" [on Michele Murray] The National Observer, 1974 Nov 23 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Levertov, Denise. Letter to the Editor, New York Times Book Review, 1967 Oct 29 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Levertov, Denise. The Painter from Provence: a review of Philip Callow's Lost Earth, a life of Cezanne. Los Angeles Times Book Review, 1995 Nov 19 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Levertov, Denise. "Poetry and Revolution" [on Neruda] Free Paper [Boston, MA], 1973 Oct 31 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Levertov, Denise. "Solzhenitsyn Reconsidered" The Real Paper, 1974 Feb 20 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Levertov, Denise. "Some Thoughts on the Cease-Fire", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Lindenberger, Herbert. "Teaching Literature in the Original or in Translation: An Intellectual or a Political Problem?" ADFL Bulletin Vol. 17, no. 2, 1986 Jan (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Macy, Joanna. Bestiary. pp. 102-105 (facsimile) (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Maldonado, Catherine Cocke. "The Lady in the Red Hat" St. Luke's Review Vol. 2 no. 2, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Mandel, Maya. "Mothering" (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Manguel, Alberto. "Blind Eye/Deaf Ear" Brick: A Literary Journal no. 54, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Mann, Thomas. "The Making of 'The Magic Mountain'" The Atlantic Monthly (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Marcus, Jane. Ex Cathedra: Caroline, Cathedral, and Cloister (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Marten, Harry. "Memory Defying Cruelty: The Poetry of John Montague" NERIBLQ [sic], 1982 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - McCarthy, Colman. "A Poet of Commitment" Washington Post, 1974 Feb 12 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - McClane, Kenneth. "Walls: A Journey to Auburn" (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - McClurg, Jocelyn. "A Poet Fired by Politics and Passion", 1988 Apr 23 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - McCourt, Frank. "Sorry for your troubles" [the difficult life of a repatriated Irish family]. New Yorker.--vol. 72, no. 15 (June 10, 1996): 52 (17 pages)., 1996 June 10 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - McFee, Michael. "Wright's Pilgrimage" (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - McMullen, Marianne. "Learning in the Land of Lenin" (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - McKibben, Bill. "The end of nature" [Reflections]. New Yorker.--vol. 65, no. 30 (Sept 11,1989):47 (45 pages)., 1989 Sept. 11, includes autograph notes of Denise Levertov, p. 79 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Merton, Thomas. "Opening the Bible" (facsimile), 1970 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Merton, Thomas. "The Sacred City" (reprint) (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Meynell, Alice. "Poetry and Childhood" (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Milosz, Czeslaw. "On Exile" Parabola, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Moliere. "Sur un Pont Veuf" Le Monde Aujourd'hui, 1985 Oct 6-7 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Moody, Rick. "Whosoever: the language of mothers and sons" [short story]. New Yorker.--vol. 73, o. n4 (March 17, 1997): 106 (5 pages)., 1997 Mar. 17 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Moore, Lorrie. "People like that are the only people here." [short story]. New Yorker.--vol. 72, no. 44 (Jan 27, 1997): 58 (14 pages)., 1997 Jan. 27 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Mueller, Tom. "The Children of Magna Graecia" Hemispheres, 1996 Sep (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Murphy, Cullen. "Who Do Men Say That I Am?" The Atlantic Monthly, 1986 Dec (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Murray, Les A. "Louvres" The Three Penny Review, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 32)